https://www.avila.edu/privacy-policy/

Skip to content
Alert!
For the latest updates on Avila's COVID-19 Response:
Who we are
Our website address is: https://www.avila.edu.
What personal data we collect and why we collect it
Avila University (“we” or “us”) values its visitors’ privacy. This privacy policy summarizes what information we might collect from a registered user or other visitor (“you”), and what we will and will not do with it.
Please note that this privacy policy does not govern the collection and use of information by companies that Avila University does not control, nor by individuals not employed or managed by Avila University. If you visit a Web site that we mention or link to, be sure to review its privacy policy before providing the site with information.
It is always up to you whether to disclose personally identifiable information to us, although if you elect not to do so, we reserve the right not to register you as a user or provide you with any products or services. “Personally identifiable information” means information that can be used to identify you as an individual, such as, for example:
your name, company, email address, phone number, billing address, and shipping addressyour Avila University user ID and password (if applicable)credit card information (if applicable)any account-preference information you provide usyour computer’s domain name and IP address, indicating where your computer is located on the Internetsession data for your login session, so that our computer can ‘talk’ to yours while you are logged in
Comments
When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection. An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.
Media
If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.
Contact forms
Cookies
If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.
If you visit our login page, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.
When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.
If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.
Embedded content from other websites
Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.
These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracking your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.
Analytics
Who we share your data with
If you do provide personally identifiable information to us, either directly or through a reseller or other business partner, we will:
not sell or rent it to a third party without your permission — although unless you opt-out (see below), we may use your contact information to provide you with information we believe you need to know or may find useful, such as news about our services and products and modifications to the Terms of Service;take commercially reasonable precautions to protect the information from loss, misuse, and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction;not use or disclose the information except:as necessary to provide services or products you have ordered, such as providing it to a carrier to deliver products you have ordered;in other ways described in this privacy policy or to which you have otherwise consented;in the aggregate with other information in such a way so that your identity cannot reasonably be determined (for example, statistical compilations);as required by law, for example, in response to a subpoena or search warrant;to outside auditors who have agreed to keep the information confidential;to a successor organization in the event of a merger, acquisition, bankruptcy, or other sale or disposition of all or a portion of Avila University’s assets. The successor organization’s use and disclosure of your personally identifiable information will continue to be subject to this privacy policy unless (i) a court orders otherwise, for example, a bankruptcy court; or (ii) the successor organization gives you notice that your personally-identifiable information will be subject to the successor organization’s own privacy policy, along with an opportunity for you to opt-out (which may cause you not to be able to continue to use the www.www.avila.edu website). If you submit personally-identifiable information after such a transfer, that information may be subject to the successor entity’s privacy policy;as necessary to enforce the Terms of Service;as necessary to protect the rights, safety, or property of Avila University, its users, or others; this may include (for example) exchanging information with other organizations for fraud protection and/or risk reduction.
How long we retain your data
If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.
For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.
What rights you have over your data
If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.
Where we send your data
Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.
Your contact information
Additional information
How we protect your data
What data breach procedures we have in place
What third parties we receive data from
What automated decision making and/or profiling we do with user data
Industry regulatory disclosure requirements
External data storage sites
We may store your data on servers provided by third party hosting vendors with whom we have contracted.
Your privacy responsibilities
To help protect your privacy, be sure:
not to share your user ID or password with anyone else;to log off the Avila University Web site when you are finished;to take customary precautions to guard against “malware” (viruses, Trojan horses, bots, etc.), for example by installing and updating suitable anti-virus software.
Notice to European Union users
Avila University’s operations are located primarily in the United States. If you provide information to us, the information will be transferred out of the European Union (EU) to the United States. By providing personal information to us, you are consenting to its storage and use as described herein.
Information collected from children
You must be at least 13 years old to use Avila University’s Web site(s) and service(s). Avila University does not knowingly collect information from children under 13. (See the [U.S.] Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act.)
Changes to this privacy policy
We reserve the right to change this privacy policy as we deem necessary or appropriate because of legal compliance requirements or changes in our business practices. If you have provided us with an email address, we will endeavor to notify you, by email to that address, of any material change to how we will use personally identifiable information.
Questions or comments?
If you have questions or comments about Avila University’s privacy policy, or contact us at Avila University, 11901 Wornall Road, Kansas City, Missouri 64145 or call 816.501.2400.
Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA)
FERPA
The Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act affords students certain rights with respect to their education records. These rights apply to all students in attendance at a post-secondary institution. These rights include:
The right to inspect and review the student’s education record . Students should submit to the University Registrar a signed written request that identifies the record(s) they wish to inspect. Arrangements for access will be made within 45 days of the day the University receives the signed written request for access. The student will be notified of the time and place where the records may be inspected.
The right to request the amendment of the student’s education records that the student believes are inaccurate, misleading, or in violation of the student’s right to privacy. Students may request an amendment to the educational record by submitting a request in writing to the University Registrar. The request must state the specific portion of the education records the student believes is inaccurate, misleading, or in violation of their privacy rights and, if appropriate, state the correct information that should be in the records. After a review of the student’s request, the student will receive a decision in writing. If the University decides not to amend the record as requested by the student, the notification to the student will advise the student of his or her right to a hearing, and the hearing procedures. NOTE: The Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act was not intended to provide a process to be used to question substantive judgments that are correctly recorded. Under this, students may not request amendments to grades that are recorded as issued by the faculty, outcomes to disciplinary hearings, reflections, or judgments recorded as part of an evaluation process, or other judgments correctly recorded. Students must refer to other institutional procedures to address these concerns.
The right to limit disclosures of some personally identifiable information contained in the student’s education records. To release personally identifiable information the student must provide a signed request/release to the appropriate office. FERPA does allow the release of personally identifiable information under the following conditions.
Directory information. Avila University has identified the following information as directory information that may be released without a student’s written consent: verification of enrollment status (full-time, part-time, graduate, undergraduate, and classification), name, major and minor field of study, academic honors, degrees awarded, dates of attendance, participation in campus activities and sports, weight and height (only if a member of an athletic team), most recent educational agency or institution attended, hometown, and photograph. Student addresses, email addresses, and telephone numbers will be released without the student’s consent only in connection with campus events and to persons with a legitimate reason. Students have the option to opt-out of the release of all or part of directory information. This request must be provided in writing to the Registrar no later than the second week of the semester. Signed written requests to limit the release of directory information must be received in the Registration & Student Records Office by the end of the second week of the semester and will remain in force until rescinded in writing.
School officials with legitimate educational interests. At Avila University, a school official has a legitimate educational interest if the official needs to review an education record in order to fulfill his or her professional responsibility. This school official may be in an administrative, supervisory, academic, research, or support staff position, a person or company with whom the University has contracted, a person serving on the Board of Trustees, or a student serving on an official committee or assisting another school official in performing his or her tasks. The Registrar is responsible for determining if a person has a legitimate educational interest to view education records. The Vice President for Student Affairs will determine legitimate educational interest for disciplinary records.
Officials at another school or institution to which a student seeks or intends to enroll.
Parents of dependent students. Before Avila University can release any personally identifiable information for a dependent student, the parent must provide proof of dependency. This must be provided each year to show continued dependency.
Lawfully issued subpoena or court order. Upon receipt of a lawfully issued subpoena or court order, FERPA requires the institution to notify the student at the student’s last known address. The student will be allowed 10 working days to block disclosure if they choose. (Blocking disclosure would require the student to obtain legal counsel at their own expense.) Exceptions to the wait time for disclosure are only in the event of a Grand Jury Subpoena OR if the judge has ordered that the request not be disclosed to the student prior to the release of the information.
Emergency Situations.
To authorized representatives of the Comptroller General of the United States, the Attorney General of the United States, or The Secretary.
State and local educational authorities.
In connection with financial aid for which the student has applied or which the student has received. This information is released if the information is necessary for such purposes as to determine eligibility for the aid, determine the amount of the aid, determine the conditions for the aid, or enforce the terms and conditions of the aid.
The right to file a complaint with the U.S. Department of Education concerning alleged failures by the University to comply with the requirements of FERPA. Complaints should be filed in writing to the following address:
Family Policy Compliance Office
U.S. Department of Education
400 Maryland Avenue, SW
Washington, DC 20202-5920
As of January 3, 2012, the U.S. Department of Education’s FERPA regulations expands the circumstances under which your education records and personally identifiable information (PII) contained in such records — including your Social Security Number, grades, or other private information — may be accessed without your consent. First, the U.S. Comptroller General, the U.S. Attorney General, the U.S. Secretary of Education, or state and local education authorities (“Federal and State Authorities”) may allow access to your records and PII without your consent to any third party designated by a Federal or State Authority to evaluate a federal- or state-supported education program. The evaluation may relate to any program that is “principally engaged in the provision of education,” such as early childhood education and job training, as well as any program that is administered by an education agency or institution. Second, Federal and State Authorities may allow access to your education records and PII without your consent to researchers performing certain types of studies, in certain cases even when we object to or do not request such research. Federal and State Authorities must obtain certain use-restriction and data security promises from the entities that they authorize to receive your PII, but the Authorities need not maintain direct control over such entities. In addition, in connection with Statewide Longitudinal Data Systems, State Authorities may collect, compile, permanently retain, and share without your consent PII from your education records, and they may track your participation in education and other programs by linking such PII to other personal information about you that they obtain from other Federal or State data sources, including workforce development, unemployment insurance, child welfare, juvenile justice, military service, and migrant student records systems.
Donor Privacy Policy
Privacy for Donors
Avila University respects the privacy of all donors. The following is our donor privacy policy, which guides our staff and volunteers on the safeguarding of your personal information.
Donor information is maintained and stored within a secure donor management database. Access to the database is restricted to personnel with legitimate business needs to access or modify the information contained therein. Your name, address, and any other personal data you provide will be used only by Avila University to keep you informed of our activities including our programs, special events, and funding needs. If at any time you choose not to receive these communications, you may contact the institution and we will gladly remove your name from our mailing list.
Avila keeps a record of each donor’s giving history. This information is kept on file for IRS purposes and is also used in our development process to analyze overall giving patterns in order to make accurate budget projections. Avila annually publishes a list of donors. We respect all donor requests to remain anonymous.
Security of Donor Information
Avila University does not rent, sell, give away, or trade its donor lists or any information contained on those lists. Donor information is used by the institution for charitable purposes only as described above and will not be used by any entity outside of the institution.
Authorized Release of Information
Avila University may be legally required to disclose information on occasion. Avila complies with all applicable legal requirements and standards.
If you have any questions about this Donor Privacy Policy or if you wish to be removed from our e-mail/postal contact lists, please contact Maggie Mohrfeld, interim Vice President of Advancement.
Go back to the top
Front Page
Apply
Visit
Request Info
Academics
Explore Programs
College of Liberal Arts & Social Sciences
